### **Contact**



+1 226-606-6590



orusaishtiaq@gmail.com



linkedin.com/orusa-akhtar



github.com/orusaish



orusaish.github.io

### **Technical Skills**

**JavaScript** 

HTML

**CSS** 

Python

Bash

Java

C#

C/C++

### **Frameworks**

Node.js

MongoDB

MySQL

**Express** 

**HandleBars** 

Sequelize

React

**Firebase** 

**Axios** 

**JQuery** 

Git

# **Orusa Akhtar**

# Summary

A full stack web developer with a passion for frontend and backend Web development. Enjoys working in a team environment and collaborating to create meaningful web applications. Certified in full stack web development from the University of Toronto and holding a Masters in Computer Applications. Experienced in web development using the MERN stack and latest industry standards.

# **Projects**

### ParkEZ





- A web app that helps truckers and truck companies reserve and view parking spaces
- Built using React, Nodejs, Express, JavaScript, Sequelize, Passport, axios, bootstrap and MySQL

### Train Scheduler





- A web app to display train arrival and departure information
- Built using moment.js, HTML, CSS and JavaScript

#### Bamazon





- An Amazon like storefront that helps maintain inventory and customer support
- Built using MySQL and Nodejs

# **Experience**

### Freelance Web Developer

Jan 2019 - Present

Designing and developing web pages for local businesses.

Home Tutor 2006-2018

Tutored middle and high school students in Math

#### Math and Science Teacher

2004-2006

Taught math and science to grade 9 and 10 students in the International Indian School, Jeddah

## Assistant Computer Science Professor

2002-2004

Sri Sathya Sai Arts and Science college, Bhopal India

- Taught data structures and database management systems
- Assisted students in programming assignments and debugging issues

# **Education**

# Full-stack web development Certificate

University of Toronto, Mississauga Bootcamp.

## Master of Computer Application (MCA)

Samrat Ashok Technological Institute, Vidisha, India

### Bachelor of Science (BSc)

Barkatullah University, Bhopal India